colorincolorado.org 2010-10-10

# Colorín Colorado :: Privacy Policy

Teachers who work with English as a Second Language learners will find ESL/ESOL/ELL/EFL reading/writing skill-building children's books, stories, activities, ideas, strategies to help PreK-3, 4-8, and 9-12 students learn to read.

A bilingual site for families and educators of English language learners

Protecting the privacy of our web site visitors is very important to us. Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we want to make sure you understand the ways in which we may and may not use the information you transmit to us when you visit Colorín Colorado. This statement discloses the privacy practices for all WETA web sites.

The information gathered by Colorín Colorado falls into two categories: (1) information voluntarily supplied by visitors to Colorín Colorado and (2) tracking information routinely gathered as visitors navigate through our site.

## Voluntarily-supplied information

To make use of certain features on Colorín Colorado you need to register and provide certain information as part of the registration process. The information you supply will help us to offer you more personalized features and to tailor our sites to your interests and make them more useful to you. Colorín Colorado does not collect any personally-identifying information unless you choose to provide that information to us.

The more you tell us about yourself, the more value we can offer you. Supplying such information is entirely voluntary. But if you don't supply the information we need, we may be unable to provide you with services we make available to other visitors to our sites. For example, we can't offer you subscription to electronic newsletters and we can't send you e-mail alerting you to any new service we're offering or breaking news that may interest you if you don't tell us your preferences and give us your e-mail address. Of course, even if you want to remain completely anonymous you're still free to take advantage of the wealth of content available on our site without registration.

The areas of the site in which we collect information, the information collected, and the purpose for collecting that information are described below:

### Subscription to electronic newsletters, online events, and online courses

Colorín Colorado offers free electronic newsletters to users. The newsletters include highlights of Colorín Colorado web site content and other news of interest. Colorín Colorado also offers occasional online discussion events and online courses. To sign up, you must provide your e-mail address, first and last name, and you must choose a password. Other information is optional. To remove yourself from any of the mailing lists, you can sign in using your e-mail address and password and unsubscribe.

### Submitting a "Bright Idea that Works," nominating a "Story from the Heart," or posing a question in "Got Questions?"

To submit any of the above to Colorín Colorado, you must enter a name and e-mail address, and of course, fill out the appropriate form for the section you are submitting to. This information is used to respond to your question, in aggregate form for statistical purposes, and may be generalized without personally identifiable information so other visitors may benefit from the information submitted.

### Sending feedback to Colorín Colorado through the "Contact Us" page

To send e-mail to Colorín Colorado through the "Contact Us" page, you must enter a name and e-mail address. This information is used to respond to your comments, in aggregate form for statistical purposes, and for promotional purposes without personally identifiable information.

Visitors under the age of 18 must obtain permission from their parents or guardians before sending any personally-identifying information to Colorín Colorado.

## Tracking information

Colorín Colorado' web server automatically collects and logs limited information about your computer's connection to the Internet when you visit our site. The information collected in these log files allows us to make our site more useful to our visitors. The access logs do NOT record your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, credit card number, or any other personally-identifying information. Rather, they contain some or all of the following information:

  * The Internet Protocol Address (IP Address) of the machine you used to access our web site*
  * The date and time you visited
  * The pages you visited on our site
  * The brand and version of browser you used, and the type of computer you used.
  * A list of files you downloaded or viewed
  * The amount of time you spent viewing or listening to streaming media files
  * Any errors you encountered

*Your IP address is a number that lets computers attached to the Internet know where to send you data. Your IP address does not identify you personally. Most Internet Service Providers use a "dynamic" form of assigning IP Addresses. This means that you may have a different IP Address each time you visit Colorín Colorado. Also, many Internet Service Providers, including America Online, use "Proxy servers" which provide even more anonymity for visitors. For example, all visitors accessing Colorín Colorado through America Online will be recorded in our access logs as having the same IP Address.

## About cookies

To help make our sites more responsive to the needs of our visitors, we invoke a standard feature found in browser software, called a "cookie," to assign each visitor a unique, random number, a sort of anonymous user ID that resides on your computer. The cookie doesn't actually identify the visitor, just the computer that a visitor uses to access our site. Unless you voluntarily identify yourself (through registration, for example), we won't know who you are, even if we assign a cookie to your computer. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply. A cookie can't read data off your hard drive, and our cookie can't read the cookie files created by other sites. Our sponsors may also assign their own cookies to your browser to track which ads you have viewed, a process that we don't control.

We use cookies to help us tailor our site to your needs, to deliver a better, more personalized service. We may also use cookies to track the pages on our site visited by our users. We can build a better site if we know which pages our users are visiting and how often.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. You do not need to have cookies enabled to use Colorín Colorado. However, some features of our site will not work properly if you refuse cookies.

## Information sharing and sites beyond Colorín Colorado

To make our site more valuable to our visitors, we offer some features in conjunction with other providers. Our online Store, for example, is made available through an affiliate arrangement with Resolution, Inc. And, of course, our site includes links to plenty of other web sites whose privacy policies we don't control. Once you leave our server (you can tell where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you're visiting. That policy may differ from ours. If you can't find the privacy policy of any of these sites via a link from the site's homepage, you should contact the site directly for more information.

## Acceptance of the Colorín Colorado privacy policy

By using this site, you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions of this Colorín Colorado Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to these terms and conditions, please do not use this site. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for any changes. Your continued use of Colorín Colorado following the posting of any changes to these terms shall mean that you have accepted those changes. If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us.

I recently found your website and it is very informative. You have found a way to teach ELLs in a more objective method and I applaud you for that. God Bless you all for your efforts to make our society aware of the need to teach English to those who come to make their dreams a reality in our country.   
~ Arthur G.
